hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our obstacle
topic let's look at our next test
automation obstacle which is called red
stripe now here what we need to do is we
need to click on the button which is lab
will generate this button okay so once
we click there a number appears uh on
the below uh in this case it is
62 and then uh this particular number it
informs you how far to the right from
the edge of the screen the red stripe
appears okay so there is a red stripe on
the screen you can see it is appearing
and this number is telling you how far
to the right this particular red stripe
is appearing on the
screen so this particular value uh which
is displayed it is nothing but the
percentage of your screen width okay now
what we need to do is we need to click
on the red stripe which appears on the
screen okay so if it appears here I need
to go ahead and click here and once I do
that then the automation obstacle is
completed okay so we need to do this
using tosa so let's see how we can
automate this particular automation
obstacle using
tosa so coming back to our tosa
commander and here uh let's go ahead and
scan this particular application
now okay so I need both the uh objects
first the generate button and then I
also need this particular object which
displays the number right so here we can
see that the okay button is displayed so
I can select that and that will get
added into the module but I don't have
the particular number which is displayed
below the button right and that
particular element is currently hidden
so what I can do is I can increase the
filtered items level okay so let's go to
the next level still I cannot see that
and let's go one more level down and now
you can see this is the div element okay
so this is the number uh which is a div
element and when I select this the item
is unique and if I go through the
properties of this Dev element you can
see it has got a ID through which it can
identify this and the inner HTML
contains the number the outer text as
well contains the number and as well as
the inner text okay so all these
properties have that particular number
so once I identify this particular
element I can get the property value and
that will contain that particular number
okay so those are the two elements which
we require in this particular module so
I'm going to rename this
module and then let's save it and we'll
close this now we'll go back to our tosa
and we are going to create a new test
case
here okay and then uh we are going to
add the module right here okay so let's
look at the test steps now so the first
step is obviously to click on the
generate button so you know we can do
that using X or the click method here I
will use the X okay and now we need to
extract the number from this particular
div element okay so for that uh we can
use the action mode buffer and then uh
we can get the inner text value and put
it into a buffer
which we call it num okay so that
particular number which is displayed
will be uh stored in this particular
buffer and we can use that later now
this uh particular step okay so it will
click on the generate button and then it
will uh grab that particular number so
now the remaining part of the automation
is to click on the red stripe once it
appears right so for that we need to use
a different U module right so let's go
ahead and search for a click on screen
module okay so you can see this is the
module which we can use okay it is part
of the tbox X engines HTML um and here
you can actually pass the XY coordinates
uh to click on a particular um part of
the screen okay and there are two
methods you can see one is HTML and one
is related to Mobile so need to select
the HTML uh module okay so once you do
that uh you will see uh the click on
screen it has got three attributes one
is caption uh one is the x coordinate
and one is y coordinate right now the
caption uh is basically your screen or
your application title so here you can
see it is stent is obstacle codes so I
can give the same here okay uh so I'm
not going to type the whole title here
I'm going to up put a regular expression
which can cover the remaining part of
the title so that becomes my caption and
then the x and y coordinate uh could be
the number okay uh so the buffer which
we have stored so we are going to get
that buffer value now
here and we are going to enter it
okay so uh basically we can uh choose
the x coordinate which is basically the
width which is displayed as the number
but uh y coordinate you can put any
value but uh it will be better if we use
the same value so that it clicks on a
particular Point uh in your screen so
this will basically uh complete your
automation obstacle now I will mark this
as completed and let's see whether it is
able to click on the button or not right
so let's go ahead head and bring this to
the initial state so let's go ahead and
run this in
scratchbook so as you can see it clicked
on the generate button and then um the
17 number appeared which means uh the
width of the screen is 17 and then uh it
went and it clicked on the red stripe
okay so it took the width and it took
the height as well okay so it was the
same number but as I said you can put
any number for the height or the
y-coordinate but the x coordinate should
be uh your number which is generated by
the application so this way you can use
the click on screen uh module which is
part of the tbox extension to pass the X
and Y coordinates and then you can click
on any particular coordinate on your
screen depending on the width and height
okay so this is one more way of uh using
the click method apart from using the
regular click method you can also use
the click on screen method uh whenever
it is required as per your
requirements that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next
video